Charles Scribner's Sons Art Reference Department
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Charles Scribner's Sons Art Reference Department records
1839-1962
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Charles Scribner's Sons
7.0 linear feet
The records of the Charles Scribner's Sons Art Reference Department measure 7.0 linear feet and date from 1839 to 1962. The records of the department include original art works, photographs, scattered letters, and miscellaneous printed material reflecting the portraiture and other illustration work completed in support of the wide range of materials and topics published by Charles Scribner's Sons over the company's long publishing history.
Historical Note
Charles Scribner's Sons was founded as a publishing partnership of Isaac D. Baker and Charles Scribner in 1846. The company set out to discover and publish the work of new American authors. The first work to be published was The Puritans and Their Principles by Edwin Hall, followed by many theological treatises, and the first bestseller, Napoleon and His Marshals by the Rev. J. T. Headley.
After Isaac Baker's death in 1850, Charles Scribner continued to direct the company which was primarily known for its books on religion. In the mid-1860s, Scribner published an American version of German author Johann Peter Lange's Biblical Commentary on the Holy Scriptures. Co-published with T. and T. Clark of Edinburgh, the resulting twenty-six volume work was both a commercial and critical success. Almost a century later, the two publishing houses again collaborated on a revision of Hasting's Dictionary of the Bible.
In 1865, Charles Scribner and Company expanded its range into magazine publishing with the quasi-religious Hours at Home that promoted the virtues by which Americans were supposed to live. In 1870 a new firm, Scribner & Company, was formed to publish a successor magazine entitled Scribner's Monthly. The magazine thrived and began to attract young American writers.
Charles Scribner died of typhoid in Lucerne, Switzerland on August 26, 1871, leaving the business to his eldest son, John Blair Scribner. In 1873 Scribner & Company launched a children's periodical, St. Nicholas, under the editorship of Mary Mapes Dodge, with Frank R. Stockton as assistant editor. The magazine brought many now-classic books to the publishing firm and established it permanently in the field of children's literature.
The 1870s saw the growth of the subscription book department. In association with Messrs. Black of Edinburgh, Scribners brought out the first American edition of the Encyclopaedia Britannica, selling 70,000 sets. In later years the subscription department published library sets of the works of well-known authors including J. M. Barrie, Henry James, Rudyard Kipling, and Robert Louis Stevenson. Its successor, the reference book department, became the foremost American publisher of reference works such as the Dictionary of American Biography, the Dictionary of American History.
In 1875, Charles Scribner II joined his brother, John Blair Scribner, and other partners, Edward Seymour and Andrew Armstrong, in the firm. Seymour died in 1877, and Armstrong sold his share to the Scribner's in 1878, leaving the book publishing company wholly controlled by the Scribner family. The name was changed to Charles Scribner's Sons. John Blair Scribner died in 1879, leaving his brother to manage the business.
In 1881 one of the outside partners, Roswell Smith, bought up enough stock to acquire individual control of Scribner & Company, the magazine company. Thus, Scribner's Monthly and the children's magazine St. Nicholas passed entirely out of the hands of the Scribner family. The remaining owners were reincorporated as the Century Company and Scribner's Monthly was renamed the Century Magazine. Charles Scribner's Sons agreed to stay out of the magazine publishing business for five years.
Charles Scribner II was joined by his younger brother, Arthur Hawley Scribner, in 1884, and during their almost fifty year partnership, they focused the company's business on publishing American literature. The publications of this period include Frances Hodgson Burnett's Little Lord Fauntleroy, Howard Pyle's The Merry Adventure of Robin Hood, and Robert Louis Stevenson's A Child's Garden of Verses. A popular series of books, "Scribner Illustrated Classics" became famous for their illustrations by Howard Pyle, Jessie Willcox Smith, N. C. Wyeth, and other members of the Brandywine school. In 1889, Henry Adams published his History of the United States in nine volumes.
Following the five-year moratorium on magazine publishing, the firm re-entered the magazine market and introduced the new Scribner's Magazine in December 1886. Under its original editor, Edward L. Burlingame, the magazine grew into a profitable enterprise and was an important venue for new authors, including Edith Wharton, who would follow their magazine debuts with many successful books. By the turn of the 20th century, Scribner's had virtually cornered the market in American literature and was enjoying a golden age of American book publishing. During this period, authors included Henry James, Theodore Roosevelt, and Elizabeth Wharton. In 1913, Charles Scribner III joined the firm.
During the 1920s, many important new authors were published, including James Boyd, F. Scott Fitzgerald, Ernest Hemingway, Ring Lardner, and Thomas Wolfe. In 1928, Charles Scribner II turned over the presidency to his younger brother Arthur, who began the publication of the first volumes of the Dictionary of American Biography. Charles Scribner II died in 1930 and Arthur Scribner died two years later, leaving Charles Scribner III to preside alone. In spite of the Depression, Charles Scribner's Sons continued to promote new authors including Taylor Caldwell, Marcia Davenport, Nancy Hale, and Marjorie Kinnan Rawlings. During the 1930s a separate children's department was established by Alice Dalgliesh. In 1937, Scribner's Magazine folded after fifty years of publication. The Dictionary of American History was published in 1940.
Charles Scribner III died suddenly in 1952, necessitating the relocation of Charles Scribner IV from his employment as a cryptoanalyst in Washington, D.C. to take charge of the firm in New York. He established the Scribner Library, a line of quality paperbacks that included the titles The Great Gatsby, Tender Is the Night, The Sun Also Rises, and Ethan Frome. Scribner also set out to develop fields of non-fiction such as history, biography, how-to books, and reference works including the Album of American History, and the Dictionary of Scientific Biography.
Scope and Content Note
The records of the Charles Scribner's Sons Art Reference Department measure 7.0 linear feet and date from 1839 to 1962. The records of the department include original art works, photographs, scattered letters, and miscellaneous printed material reflecting the portraiture and other illustration work completed in support of the wide range of materials and topics published by Charles Scribner's Sons over the company's long publishing history.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into 3 alphabetically-arranged series. Oversized material from all series have been housed in Box 7 (Sol), Box 8 (Sol), and OVs 9 - 12. Notations for the oversized materials are noted at the appropriate folder title with see also/see references
Series 1: Portrait Files, 1839-1962, undated (Boxes 1-5, 7, OV 11; 4.5 linear feet)
Series 2: Illustrator Files, 1878-1921, undated (Box 5, 6, 8-OV12; 1.5 linear feet)
Series 3: Miscellaneous Reference Files, 1933-1952, undated (Box 6, 8, OV 12; 1.0 linear feet)
Index Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following index terms. People, families and organizations are listed under "Subjects" when they are the topic of collection contents and under "Names" when they are creators or contributors.
Subjects-Topical:
Scribner's Monthly; Photographers; Designers -- Great Britain; Illustrators -- Great Britain; Portrait painters -- New York (State) -- New York; Sculptors -- France
Types of Materials:
Works of art; Photographs; Sketches
Names:
Berger, William Merritt, b. 1872
Provenance
The Charles Scribner's Sons Art Reference Department records were donated in 1957 and 1958 by Charles Scribner's Sons.
Restrictions on Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment.
Alternative Forms Available
The collection was digitized in 2010 and is available via the Archives of American Art's website.
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Portrait Files, 1839-1962, undated, Series 1:; (Boxes 1-5, 7, OV 12; 4.4 linear feet)
  These files primarily contain portraits of historic individuals from ancient times through the first half of the 20th century. Many are original drawings, prints, and paintings by miscellaneous artists including Otto Bacher, Carroll Beckwith, Jay Norwood (Ding) Darling, James Montgomery Flagg, Valerian Gribayédoff, Lydia Hess, Sid Hydeman, William L. Metcalf, Waldo Peirce, George T. Tobin, and Elisabeth Louise Vigée Le Brun. Portrait photographs by notable photographers include Elizabeth of Belgium by Keturah Collings, Carolus Duran by Nadar, and John Galsworthy by Arnold Genthe.
  Several files contain additional related photographs and printed material, including photographs of the homes of Lawrence Alma-Tadema, Captain Cook, Goethe, Sir Francis Seymour Haden, Nathaniel Hawthorne, Victor Hugo, Jean-François Millet, Samuel F. B. Morse, Napoleon, Captain Ernest Peixotto, Ernst Renan, John Ruskin, William Makepease Thackeray, Martin Van Buren, George Washington, and William Wordsworth.
  Additional photographs depict the death masks of Robert Burns and Felix Mendelssohn; Kaiser Wilhelm on army maneuvers; ceremonies marking the bicentennial of the death of Racine; and Frederic Remington with colleagues Richard Harding Davis, Stephen Bonsal, and Caspar Whitney. There is also a letter from John Lockwood Kipling discussing sketches of India.
  This series has been scanned in its entirety.
  - Unidentified Subjects, undated, (Oversized items housed in Box 7) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Abigail Smith Adams; Hannah Adams; Henry Adams, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - J. T. Adams, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - John Adams, undated, (Oversized items housed in Box 7) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - John Quincy Adams; Samuel Adams, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Joseph Addison, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Madame S.A.R. Adelaide; Gustavus Adolphus, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Louis Aggasiz, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Carl Ethan Akeley; Alaric; Duke of Alba; Duke of Albemarle, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Dr. Heinrich E. Albert; Prince Albert, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Louisa May Alcott, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - H. M. Alden, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Thomas Bailey Aldrich, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Vittorio Alfieri, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - King Alfonso XIII of Spain; King Alfred; Ethan Allen; Edward Alleyn, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - William B. Allison, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Lawrence Alma-Tadema, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Cardinal Antonelli; Antoninus Pius; Thomas Aquinas; Aulo Licinio Archias; Archimedes, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Sir Edwin Arnold; Matthew Arnold; Sophie Arnold; Thomas Arnold; King Arthur; Stanley M. Arthurs; Count of Artois, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Lord Ashburton; Clifford Ashley; Lady Ashley; Ashur-Nasir-Apal; Attila, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Emile Augier; Augustus Caesar; Jane Austen; Alfred Austin; William Austin; Anne of Austria, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - H. Baass; Maltbie Davenport Babcock; Johann Ambrosius Bach; Johann Sebastian Bach; Philipp Emanuel Bach; Wilhelm Friedmann Bach, undated, (Oversized items housed in Box 7) (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Sir Francis Bacon, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Newton D. Baker; Samuel Baker; Marcus Balbus, the Elder; Marcus Balbus, theYounger; Nonius Balbus; Arthur James Balfour, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Honoré de Balzac, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Aaron Bancroft, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - George Bancroft, undated, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 27-28)
  - Lucretia Bancroft; A. J. Barnow; Elizabeth Barry, undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Frederic A. Bartholdi, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Antoine Louis Barye; Rev. Richard Baxter; René Bazin, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Daniel C. Beard, undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - G. T. Beauregard; Rev. G. T. Bedell; Beethoven, undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Alexander Graham Bell, undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Alva Smith Belmont; Caroline Perry Belmont, undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Jacinto Benavente, undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Wladyslaw Theodore Benda, undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Egbert Benson; Thomas Hart Benton; Dr. George Berkeley; Thomas Bertram; Bernardo Bini, 1931, undated, (Oversized items housed in Box 7) (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Reginald Birch, undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Bjornstjerne Bjornson, undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Richard Doddridge Blackmore, 1903-1904 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Admiral Blake; William Rufus Blake, undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Blanche, undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Robert Blum, undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Anne Boleyn; Commodore Bolton, undated (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Charles L. Bonaparte, undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Muirhead Bone; Daniel Boone; Nicolas Boileau-Despréaux, undated (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - St. John Bosco; Jacques Benigne Bossuet; Matthew Boulton; Boyd, undated, (Oversized items housed in Box 7) (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Johannes Brahms; Prof. Charles A. Briggs; Charles Brockden Brown; David Brown; Rev. John Brown; Sir Thomas Browne, undated (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Robert Browning; Elizabeth Barrett Browning, 1899, undated (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - William Cullen Bryant; James Buchanan; John Bunyan; Henry Burbeck; Edmund Burke, 1880, undated, (Oversized items housed in Box 7) (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Edward Burne-Jones, undated (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Frances Hodgson Burnett, undated (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - David Hudson Burnham, undated (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Robert Burns, undated (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Aaron Burr; Sir Richard F. Burton, undated (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Benjamin Franklin Butler, undated (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Charles Butler, undated (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - George Gordon Noel (Lord) Byron, 1924, undated, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 59-60)
  - George Washington Cable, undated (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Julius Caesar, undated (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - M. Callaghan; V. F. Calverton; John Calvin; Duchess of Cambridge, undated, (Oversized items housed in Box 7) (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Thomas Carlyle, 1839, undated, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 64-65)
  - Nicolas Leonard Sadi Carnot; Jacques Cartier; Dr. Edmund Cartwright; Catherine de Medici; Catherine of Aragon; Catherine of Russia, undated (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Benvenuto Cellini, undated (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Miguel de Cervantes, undated (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Thomas Chalmers; Chantilly, undated (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Charles Shepard Chapman, undated (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Charlotte Charke, undated (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Charlemagne, 1930, undated (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Charles I, undated (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Charles II, undated (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Charles V; Charles X; Charles XII of Sweden, undated (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Queen Charlotte; Lord Chatham; Geoffrey Chaucer, undated (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Anton Chekhov; Earl of Chesterfield; Frédéric Chopin; William Dougal Christie; Winston Churchill, undated (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Colley Cibber; Theophilus Cibber, undated (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Cicero; Cincinnatus; Earl of Clarendon, undated (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Henry Clay, undated (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Cleopatra; Robert Clive; François Clouet; Clovis, undated (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Jacques-Nicolas Colbert; Samuel Taylor Coleridge; Admiral Coligny; Prince of Condé; Confucius; Roscoe Conkling, undated (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Benjamin Constant, undated (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - J. H. Constant, undated (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Constantine; Captain Cook; Sir Eyre Coote; Copeland; Copernicus; Corbulon, undated, (Oversized items housed in Box 7) (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Giles Corey; Barry Cornwall; Charles Cornwallis, undated (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Jean-Baptiste-Camille Corot, undated (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - Royal Cortissoz, undated (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - Mrs. Unwin Cowper, undated (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - Kenyon Cox, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Archbishop Cranmer; Elizabeth Cromwell; Henry Cromwell, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Oliver Cromwell, 1899, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Richard Cromwell; Suydam Cutting; Georges Cuvier, 1935, undated, (Oversized items housed in Box 7) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Dagnan-Bouveret; J. D'Alembert; William Dampier; Dr. Leopold Damrosch, undated, (Oversized items housed in Box 7) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Jay Norwood (Ding) Darling, 1928-1962, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - C. Darress ?, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Alphonse Daudet, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Thomas Davidson, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Davies; Charles Belmont Davis, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Richard Harding Davis, 1897-1912, undated, (6 Folders; oversized items housed in Box 7) (Box 2, Folder 11-16)
  - Monsieur De Calonne; John Deere; Demosthenes; Descartes; Hernando De Soto; Charles Henri-Hector D'Estaing; Pedro de Valdivia; Robert Devereux, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - E. M. de Witte; Rev. Thomas Frognall Dibdin, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Charles Dickens, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Edward Dickinson; Benjamin Disraeli; Austin Dobson; William Dobson, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Sir Francis Drake; John Dryden, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - George Du Maurier; W. W. Duncan, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Peter Finley Dunne, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Joseph François Dupleix, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Carolus Duran, undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Timothy Dwight, undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Elizabeth I of England, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Elizabeth of Belgium, undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Elizabeth Shippen Green Elliot, undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Ralph Waldo Emerson; Erasmus; King Ethelbert; Empress Eugénie; Edward Everett, undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Sir Thomas Fairfax; Michael Faraday; Admiral David G. Farragut; Faustina, undated, (Oversized items housed in Box 7) (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Ferdinand of Spain; Jules Ferry; Henry M. Field; George P. Fisher, undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Harrison Fisher, 1911, undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - F. Scott Fitzgerald, undated, (Oversized items housed in Box 7) (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Mrs. Fitzherbert, undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - James Montgomery Flagg, undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - General Fleetwood; Peter Fleming; François Fournier-Sarloveze; C. J. Fox; John Franklin, undated, (Oversized items housed in Box 7) (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - W. A. Fraser, undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Frederick I (Barbarossa); Frederick the Great; Martin Frobisher, undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - A. B. Frost, undated (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - James Anthony Froude, undated (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Gainsborough; Galileo, undated (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - John Galsworthy, undated, (5 folders; oversized items housed in Box 7, OV 11) (Box 2, Folder 43-47)
  - Gambetta; George III; George IV; Gerard, undated (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Jean-Léon Gérôme, undated (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Sir Humphrey Gilbert; Christoph Willibald Gluck, undated (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Goethe, 1886-1907, undated, (3 folders) (Box 2, Folder 51-53)
  - Edmund de Goncourt, undated (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - George Goodspeed; Charles George "Chinese" Gordon; Gracchi Brothers; James Graham; Charles Gravier, undated, (Oversized items housed in Box 7) (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Alice Gray; Effie Gray; George Gray; Sophie Gray; A. W. Greeley; S. W. Green, undated (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Kate Greenaway, undated (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Sir Thomas Gresham; Edvard Grieg; Countess Guiccioli, undated (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Guizot, undated (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Guttenberg; Nell Gwynne, undated (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Sir Francis Seymour Haden; John Hales; Nancy Hall, undated, (Oversized items housed in Box 7) (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - John Hampden, undated (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - George Frederick Handel; Hannibal; Thomas Hardy; William Harvey; Sir Anthony Hope Hawkins; Sir John Hawkins, undated (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Nathaniel Hawthorne, undated (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - I. T. Hening; William Ernest Henley; Henry of Guise, undated (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Henry IV of France; Henry IV of Germany; Henry VII of England; Henry VIII of England, undated (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Patrick Henry; Friedrich Herbart; George Herbert, undated (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Hercules, undated (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Oliver Herford; Augustine Herrman; William Herschel; Maurice Hewlett, undated (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Malvina Hoffman, undated (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - William Hogarth; Henry Edward, Lord Holland; J. G. Holland; Oliver Wendell Holmes, undated (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Thomas Hood; Richard Hooker; George Hudson, undated (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Victor Hugo, undated, (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 73-74)
  - King Humbert of Italy, undated (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - James Gibbons Huneker, undated, (3 folders) (Box 2, Folder 76-78)
  - Governor Hunt; Holman Hunt; Leigh Hunt; John Huse of Bohemia; Constantin Huygens, undated (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - William Ralph Inge, undated (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - J.A.D. Ingres; General Henry Ireton, undated (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Washington Irving; Queen Isabella of Spain, undated, (Oversized items housed in Box 7) (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Andrew Jackson, undated (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - James I of England, undated (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - John Jay; Jeanne d'Arc; General Joffre; King John of England; Sir George Johnson; Senator M. Johnson; M. E. Borough Johnson; Samuel Johnson, undated (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Inigo Jones; John Paul Jones; Ben Jonson; Empress Josephine; Dr. Joule, undated (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Kaiser Wilhelm, undated, (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 87-88)
  - John Keats; A. I. Keller; Lord Kelvin; Bishop J. M. Kendrick, undated (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - Johannes Kepler; Erasmus D. Keyes; Captain Kidd; Alonzo Kimball, undated (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - John Lockwood Kipling, 1897 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Rudyard Kipling; Jean-Baptiste Kleber, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Louis Aston Knight, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Louis Kossuth, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Jean de La Fontaine; Jean de La Marck; Lamartine; Charles Lamb, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - General Lambert; Richard Landor; Laplace; William Laud, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Francis de Laval; Antoine Lavoisier; Sir Thomas Lawrence; John Leech; Robert Le Gallienne, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Lord Frederick Leighton, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Le Verrier, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - J. C. Leyendecker, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Wilhelm Liebknecht; Abraham Lincoln, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Franz Liszt, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Bata Kindai Amgoza Ibn Lo-Bagola; John Locke; Henry Wadsworth Longfellow; King Louis Philippe, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Louis XIII; Louis XIV; Louis XV; Louis XVIII, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Will Low; James Russell Lowell; Mary Lowney, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Ignatius Loyola; Martin Luther, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Lord Thomas Babington Macaulay; Niccolo Machiavelli, undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Alexander Mackenzie; David Maclise; Marshall MacMahon; Magellan, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - H. Van Buren Magonigle, undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Nicolaus de Malezieu; Charles Manigault; Alexander Manzoni; Marat, undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Maria Theresa; Princess Marie of Holland; Queen Marie; Jean Marion; Michael de Marolles, undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Karl Marx, undated (Box 3, Folder 22)